securitynewsdesk.com 2019-10-03

# Privacy Policy - Security News Desk

Hand Media International is dedicated to ensuring the personal information we gather from visitors to our websites is treated in accordance with applicable data privacy laws.

This Privacy Policy explains how we might use the information you provide when using our websites, although you do not have to supply any information to use them. Some personal details may be necessary however, for some features of our website to work properly.

This privacy policy has been drafted to ensure compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

**Scope of our Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy applies to this website and any other websites owned or operated by Hand Media.

**How we collect your personal data**

We may collect your personal data in different ways:

  * By providing services to you, the organisation for which you work or represent;
  * By providing information associated with your attendance at any events we organise or host;
  * By filling in forms on this website or when you contact us;
  * By collecting information about you or the organisation for which you work or represent that is publicly available; and
  * By collecting your personal data from clients, consultants, suppliers or other advisers.

**The type of personal data that we may collect**

The types of personal data we might collect includes:

  * Contact details (including name, full postal address, email address and telephone numbers);
  * Professional information (including job title, professional experience and qualifications);
  * Information concerning your business and personal interests as provided by you, including attendance at our events; and
  * Details of your visits to our website (including, traffic data, location data, web logs, etc.).

**Use of personal information**

We process personal information for the following purposes:

  * To provide information and services, either requested from us or which we believe will interest those concerned, as permitted under applicable law;
  * To improve the content of our website and its methods of delivery;
  * To maintain and develop our relationship with visitors;
  * For research, planning, service development, security or risk management;
  * To undertake services we have agreed to provide;
  * To allow access to secure areas of our website; and
  * To comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.

**Marketing**

It is your right to prevent us processing your personal information for use in our marketing activities. When you provide your contact information, for example when you provide your business card, we will typically add your details to our marketing database, but at any time you can exercise your right to have yourself removed by emailing us at [info@hand-media.com](mailto:marketing@hand-media.com)

**Cookies**

This is a text file with small amounts of information that is downloaded to your computer or browsing device when you visit our site. This is presented on every return visit to our site or when you visit another site that recognises the same cookie.

These cookies will help navigation through our site by remembering your preferences and making it quicker for you to browse our site. Some can be used to target existing advertising more to your tastes and interests.

Sometimes we collect anonymous traffic data to allow our web developers to see how many people are visiting the site and how they are using it. This is purely statistical to enhance your experience of the site and no user is listed or identified.

We explain how we use cookies when you first access our site and that is your opportunity to prevent or allow us to store these cookies on your browsing device.

Some cookies on this site are essential and the site will not work as expected without them enabled. These cookies are set when you submit a form, login or interact with the site by doing something more than just clicking a simple link.

**Using your personal information**

We do not sell or rent to third-parties the information we collect through our website.

We may disclose information under certain circumstances, including:

  * When we are required by a legal, regulatory or professional obligation to do so;
  * When consent has been given for us to share the information provided;
  * When we suspect your use of our website has violated or may violate relevant laws or regulations, or if we believe you may be a threat to safety, security, interests or our rights or those of others;
  * If we outsource services that involve data processing, technology, research, banking and payment, client contact, data entry and processing, litigation support, marketing and security services and other related services; and
  * To investigate, respond to or resolve problems or address inquiries or to defend our interests, including, professional indemnity insurers, auditors, professional advisors, etc.

Hand Media and some of the third-parties we share information with, may be located outside your home country or the country from where the data was provided. If your data is transferred to these countries, we will ensure your data is protected to standard at least equal to the GDPR.

**The internet**

This website regularly links to other websites which are beyond our control and are therefore not covered by this Privacy Policy.

We accept no responsibility or liability for other sites’ privacy policies and if you access other websites through links provided on our website, please check the policies on these websites before submitting any personal information.

**Security**

Transmission of information through the internet cannot be guaranteed to be completely secure and any transmission is at your own risk.

We do our best to protect personal information, but cannot guarantee the security of the information you transmit to us through this website or by other means. Once received, your information will be protected by appropriate procedures and security features designed to prevent unauthorised access by any means.

We virus check documents and files before they are posted on any website, but cannot guarantee documents or files downloaded from our website will be free from viruses – we accept no responsibility for any damage or loss caused by any such virus.

When using our website, you should use an anti-virus app and must not provide any document or file which contains a virus, or post such to any website we own.

**Your consent**

When you submit or provide your personal information to us, you are consenting to its use as detailed in this Privacy Policy

**Updating and correcting your information**

The GDPR gives you the right to access and amend your personal information. If you would like to request a copy of the information we hold on you or would like to change this information please contact us at [info@hand-media.com](mailto:info@hand-media.com) or call us at +44 (0)1622 823920.

We want your information to be accurate and current, so if any of your information changes, like your contact number or email, please let us know the correct details by emailing [info@hand-media.com](mailto:info@hand-media.com) You can also request us to delete any information you regard as inaccurate.

**Hand Media privacy policy**

Hand Media may have to revise this Privacy Policy in the future and if we do, we will post the changes on this page so you will be aware of the information we collect and how we use it.

This Privacy Policy was last updated in September 2018, but please review this page regularly to ensure you recognise any changes to our terms of use. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please email [info@hand-media.com](mailto:info@hand-media.com)
